<?xml version='1.0'?>
<passage>
<passage-text>
<div align="center"><b>Ozette</b></div>
<br/>The availability of archeological evidence for study is dependent on the 

natural conditions in which the archeological remains are found; <exp>certain types of natural 

conditions favor preservation</exp> of organic substances <exp>and therefore lend <bg>themselves</bg> to sheltering</exp> 

well-preserved organic remains, while other types of natural conditions lead to the degradation 

or destruction of organic remains that may have existed.  An important distinction in land 

archeology can be made between dryland and wetland archeological sites.  The vast majority of 

sites are dry sites, which means that the moisture content of the material enveloping the 

archeological evidence is low and preservation of the organic material as a result is quite 

poor.  Wetland archeological sites are sites such as those found in lakes, swamps, marshes, and 

bogs; in these wetland archeological sites, organic materials are effectively sealed in an 

environment that is airless and wet and that therefore tends to foster preservation.<br/>It has 

been estimated that on a wet archeological site often 90 percent of the finds are organic.  

This is the case, however, only when the site has been more or less permanently waterlogged up 

to the time of excavation; if a wet site has dried out periodically, perhaps seasonally, 

decomposition of the organic material has most likely taken place.  Organic material such as 

textiles, leather, basketry, wood, and plant remains of all kinds tends to be well preserved in 

permanently waterlogged sites, while little or none of this type of organic material would 

survive in dryland archeological sites or in wetland sites that have from time to time dried 

out.  For this reason, archeologists have been focusing more on wet sites, which are proving to 

be rich sources of evidence about the lifestyles and activities of past human cultures.<br/>A 

serious problem with archeological finds in waterlogged environments is that the organic finds, 

and wood in particular, deteriorate rapidly when they are removed from the wet environment and 

begin to dry out.  It is therefore important that organic finds be kept wet until they can be 

treated in a laboratory; the need for extraordinary measures to preserve organic finds taken 

from wetland environments in part explains the huge cost of wetland archeology, which has been 

estimated to be quadruple the cost of dryland archeology.<br/>One wetland site that has 

produced extraordinary finds is the Ozette site, on the northwest coast of the United States in 

the state of Washington.  Around 1750, a huge mudslide that resulted from the seasonal swelling 

of an underground stream completely covered sections of a whaling village located there.  

Memories of the village were kept alive by descendants of the surviving inhabitants of the 

village in their traditional stories, and an archeological excavation of the site was 

organized.  The mud was removed from the site, and a number of well-preserved cedarwood houses 

were uncovered, complete with carved panels painted with animal designs, hearths, and benches 

for sleeping.  More than 50,000 artifacts in excellent condition were found, including woven 

material such as baskets and mats, equipment for weaving such as looms and spindles, hunting 

equipment such as bows and harpoons, fishing equipment such as hooks and rakes, equipment used 

for water transportation such as canoe paddles and bailers, containers such as wooden boxes and 

bowls, and decorative items such as a huge block of cedar carved in the shape of the dorsal fin 

of a whale and miniature carved figurines.  
</passage-text>
</passage>

