<?xml version='1.0'?>
<question-list type='read' passage-file='ASR04P00.xml'>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR04P01.xml" skills="3">
      <question-text>Which of the sentences below expresses the essential information in the highlighted sentence in paragraph 1?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>They originally intended to make computers only for themselves, but soon they were making computers for friends.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Because computer technology was widely available to consumers, they decided to limit the scope of their production.</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>Their plan changed</exp> from <exp>one of assembling computers for those already knowledgeable in computers</exp> to <exp>introducing computers to those who were not</exp>.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Their goal of making computers for broad markets was clearly set from the start.</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>3</key>
      <explain-text>
The highlighted sentence states that <exp>this goal soon changed</exp>, which means that <exp>their plan changed</exp>, that <exp>their initial idea was to assemble computers for&#8230;personal computer hobbyists</exp>, which means that their initial plan was <exp>one of assembling computers for those already knowledgeable in computers</exp>, and that the plans changed to <exp>one of making computer technology more widely available to nontechnical consumers</exp>, which means that it changed to <exp>introducing computers to those who were not</exp> knowledgeable in computers. The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>
<question type='insert' passage-file='ASR04P02.xml' skills='4'>
<insert-text><b>They intended to change <exp>this public perception of computers</exp>.</b></insert-text>
<key>4</key>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>most consumers at the time thought of computers as playthings for hobbyists and as too expensive and too complex for general use.</exp> A sentence mentioning <exp>this public perception of computers</exp> would logically follow such an idea. The last square in paragraph 1 is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
</question>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR04P03.xml" skills="3">
      <question-text>Which of the sentences below expresses the essential information in the highlighted sentence in paragraph 2?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text><exp>The product name was chosen to make their product appealing to the nontechnical market.</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>The product name was selected to put the company into different markets from other computer companies.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Because the company was not technologically oriented, a product name was chosen to clarify this.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>A name was chosen that would make the product seem less threatening to competitors.</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>1</key>
      <explain-text>
The highlighted sentences states that <exp>the name Apple was selected because</exp> it was <exp>nontechnical, nonthreatening,</exp> and <exp>would not be off-putting to their intended market</exp>. This means that <exp>the product name was chosen to make their product more appealing to the nontechnical market.</exp> The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>
<question type='insert' passage-file='ASR04P04.xml' skills='4'>
<insert-text><b>It may seem surprising, but <exp>that was all that was needed to start their company</exp>.</b></insert-text>
<key>2</key>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>Jobs and Wozniak raised $1,300 to start a company.</exp> A sentence stating that <exp>that was all that was needed to start their company</exp> would logically follow such an idea. The second square in paragraph 2 is therefore the answer to this question.
</explain-text>
</question>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR04P05.xml" skills="3">
      <question-text>Which of the sentences below expresses the essential information in the highlighted sentence in paragraph 3?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>Even though <exp>Apple I users needed to have a lot of technical knowledge, orders surprisingly reached 600.</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>Computer hobbyists preferred to use the Apple I because it allowed them to make use of their technical knowledge.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Because of the limited technical ability of the Apple I computer, it was unbelievable that 600 were ordered.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>The owners of the company needed a surprising amount of technical knowledge to reach 600 customers.</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>1</key>
      <explain-text>
The highlighted sentence states that <exp>the Apple I required the user to have a fair amount of technical knowledge</exp>, which means that <exp>Apple I users needed to have a lot of technical knowledge</exp>, and that <exp>orders for this machine&#8230;quickly reached the unbelievably high level of 600</exp>, which means that <exp>orders surprisingly reached 600</exp>. The first answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>
<question type='insert' passage-file='ASR04P06.xml' skills='4'>
<insert-text><b><exp>This machine was named the Apple I</exp>.</b></insert-text>
<key>2</key>
<explain-text>
The passage mentions <exp>their first model</exp>. A sentence stating that <exp>this machine was named the Apple I</exp> would logically follow such an idea. The second square in paragraph 4 is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
</question>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR04P07.xml" skills="3">
      <question-text>Which of the sentences below expresses the essential information in the highlighted sentence in paragraph 4?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>The special ad-on devices and software programs caused demand for the Apple II to increase.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Because of the popularity of the Apple II, a number of other companies began working on creating competing models.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Without the devices and software prepared by other companies, the Apple II was unusable.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Because <exp>the Apple II was so popular, other companies created products to go along with it</exp>.</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>4</key>
      <explain-text>
The highlighted sentence states that <exp>demand for this new version of the Apple quickly soared</exp>, which means that <exp>the Apple II was so popular</exp>, and that this <exp>inspired numerous other companies to created ad-on devices and software programs that could be used in conjunction with it</exp>, which means that <exp>other companies created products to go along with it</exp>. The last answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>
<question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR04P08.xml" skills="3">
      <question-text>Which of the sentences below expresses the essential information in the highlighted sentence in paragraph 5?</question-text>
      <answer-list>
         <answer-text>The company's personnel focused its attention on leaders, on investments, on marketing to computer hobbyists, and on improving initial computer purchases over peripherals.</answer-text>
         <answer-text>Because their innovative products were already developed, the company needed to pay attention to developing new markets for their products.</answer-text>
         <answer-text><exp>The company had a strategic plan that involved emphasis on strong personnel, innovation, research and development, market expansion, and development of peripheral products.</exp></answer-text>
         <answer-text>The company's plan was to rely more heavily on innovation and research than to work on developing markets.
</answer-text>
      </answer-list>
      <key>3</key>
      <explain-text>
The highlighted sentences mentions <exp>the company's strategic plan</exp>, and its emphasis on <exp>personnel,&#8230;innovation,&#8230;research and development&#8230;</exp>, the desire <exp>to expand their market&#8230;</exp> and <exp>&#8230;peripheral products</exp>. This means that <exp>the company had a strategic plan that involved emphasis on strong personnel, innovation, research and development, market expansion, and development of peripheral products.</exp> The third answer is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
   </question>
<question type='insert' passage-file='ASR04P09.xml' skills='4'>
<insert-text><b>To do so, they brought in <exp>a number of new employees</exp>.</b></insert-text>
<key>2</key>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>Jobs and Wozniak decided to expand their company</exp>. A sentence that mentions <exp>a number of new employees</exp> would logically follow such an idea. The second square in paragraph 5 is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
</question>
<question type='insert' passage-file='ASR04P10.xml' skills='4'>
<insert-text><b>This represented <exp>an unbelievable 14-fold increase in only two years</exp>.</b></insert-text>
<key>2</key>
<explain-text>
The passage states that <exp>revenues&#8230;grew to $8 million in 1978 and escalated exponentially to $117 million in 1980</exp>. A sentence mentioning <exp>an unbelievable 14-fold increase in only two years</exp> would logically follow such an idea. The second square in paragraph 6 is therefore the best answer to this question.
</explain-text>
</question>
</question-list>


