<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage scroll0='18' scroll='18'>
    <passage-text>
        <div align="center">
            <b>Pulsars</b>
        </div>
        <br/>
            There is still much for astronomers to learn about pulsars. Based on what is known,
        the term <b>pulsar</b> is used to describe the phenomenon of short, precisely timed radio bursts
        that are emitted from somewhere in space. Though all is not known about pulsars, they are
        now believed in reality to emanate from spinning <b>neutron stars</b>, highly reduced cores of
        collapsed stars that are theorized to exist.
        <br/>
            Pulsars were discovered in 1967, when Jocelyn Bell, a graduate student at Cambridge
        University, noticed an unusual pattern on a chart from a radio telescope. What made this
        pattern unusual was that, unlike other radio signals from celestial objects, this series of
        pulses had a highly regular period of 1.33730119 seconds. Because day after day the
        pulses came from the same place among the stars, Cambridge researchers came to the
        conclusion that they could not have come from a local source such as an Earth satellite.
        <br/>
            A name was needed for this newly discovered phenomenon. The possibility that the
        signals were coming from a distant civilization was considered, and at that point the idea
        of naming the phenomenon L.G.M. (short for Little Green Men) was raised. However, after
        researchers had found three more regularly pulsing objects in other parts of the sky over the
        next few weeks, the name pulsar was selected instead of L.G.M.
        <br/>
            As more and more pulsars were found, astronomers <bg>engaged in</bg> debates over their
        nature. It was determined that a pulsar could not be a star inasmuch as a normal star is too
        big to pulse so fast. The question was also raised as to whether a pulsar might be a white
        dwarf star, a dying star that has collapsed to approximately the size of the Earth and is
        slowly cooling off. However, this idea was also rejected because the fastest pulsar known
        at the time pulsed around thirty times per second and a white dwarf, which is the smallest
        known type of star, would not hold together if it were to spin that fast.
        <br/>
            The final conclusion among astronomers was that only a neutron star, which is
        theorized to be the remaining core of a collapsed star that has been reduced to a highly
        dense radius of only around 10 kilometers, was small enough to be a pulsar. Further
        evidence of the link between pulsars and neutron stars was found in 1968, when a pulsar
        was found in the middle of the Crab Nebula. The Crab Nebula is what remains of the
        supernova of the year 1054, and inasmuch as it has been theorized that neutron stars
        sometimes remain following supernova explosions, it is believed that the pulsar coming from
        the Crab Nebula is evidently just such a neutron star.
        <br/>
            The generally accepted theory for pulsars is the <b>lighthouse theory</b>, which is based
        upon a consideration of the theoretical properties of neutron stars and the observed
        properties of pulsars. According to the lighthouse theory, a spinning neutron star emits
        beams of radiation that sweep through the sky, and when one of the beams passes over the
        Earth, it is detectable on Earth. It is known as the lighthouse theory because the emissions
        from neutron stars are similar to the pulses of light emitted from lighthouses as they sweep
        over the ocean; the name lighthouse is therefore actually more appropriate than the name
        pulsar.
    </passage-text>
</passage>