<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage>
    <passage-text>
        <div align="center">
            <b>Theodore Dreiser</b>
        </div>
        <br/>
        	Theodore Dreiser, the American author best known for the novel <i>Sister Carrie</i> (1912),
        introduced a powerful style of writing that had a profound influence on the writers that
        followed him, from Steinbeck to Fitzgerald and Hemingway. It was in <i>Sister Carrie</i> that
        Theodore Dreiser created a fictional account that laid bare the harsh reality of life in the big
        city and in which Dreiser established himself as the architect of a new genre.
        <br/>
        	Dreiser was born in 1871 into a large family whose fortunes had in the recent past
        taken a dramatic turn for the worse. Before Theodore's birth, his father had built up a
        successful factory business only to lose it to a fire. The family was rather abruptly thrust into
        poverty, and Theodore spent his youth moving from place to place in the Midwest as the
        family tried desperately to reestablish itself financially. He left home at the age of sixteen.
        After earning some money, he spent a year at Indiana University but left school and returned
        to Chicago, yearning for the glamour and excitement that it offered. At the age of twentytwo,
        he began work as a reporter for a small newspaper in Chicago, the Daily Globe, and
        later worked on newspapers in Pittsburgh, Cleveland, Saint Louis, and New York City. <bg>In
        his work as a reporter, he was witness to the seamier side of life and was responsible for
        recording events that befell the less fortunate in the city, the beggars, the alcoholics, the
        prostitutes, and the working poor.</bg>
        <br/>
        	Dreiser first tried his hand at fiction by writing short stories rather than novels, and
        the first four short stories that he wrote were published. Based on this, he was encouraged
        to write a novel that would accurately depict the harsh life of the city, and the novel Sister
        Carrie was the result of his effort. This novel chronicles the life of Carrie Meeber, a smalltown
        girl who goes to Chicago in a quest for fame and fortune. As Carrie progresses from
        factory worker to Broadway star by manipulating anyone in her path, Dreiser sends a clear
        message about the tragedy of life that is devoted purely to the quest for money.
        <br/>
        	<i>Sister Carrie</i>, unfortunately for Dreiser, did not achieve immediate success. The novel
        was accepted for publication by Doubleday, but Dreiser was immediately asked to make
        major revisions io the novel. When Dreiser refused to make the revisions, Doubleday
        published only a limited number of copies of the book and refused to promote or advertise
        it. Published in limited release and without the backing of the company, the novel was a
        dismal failure, selling fewer than 500 copies.
        <br/>
        	After the failure of the novel that was so meaningful to him, Dresier suffered a nervous
        breakdown; he was depressed, stricken with severe headaches, and unable to sleep for
        days on end. Having sunk to a point where he was considering suicide, he was sent by his
        brother to a sanatorium in White Plains, New York, where he eventually recovered. After
        leaving the sanatorium, he took a position as an editor for Butterick's. He was successful in
        this position, and was eventually able to purchase a one-third interest in a new publishing
        company, B. W. Dodge, which republished Dreiser's novel <i>Sister Carrie</i>. This new release
        of the novel proved considerably more successful than the first release had been. In its first
        year, the reissued version of <i>Sister Carrie</i> sold 4,500 copies, with strong reviews, and the
        next year it sold more than 10,000 copies. The recognition that accompanied the success of
        the novel was based not only on the power of the description of the perils of urban life but
        also on the new trend in literature that Dreiser was credited with establishing.
    </passage-text>
</passage>