<?xml version='1.0'?>
<question-list type='read' passage-file='ASR24P00.xml'>

    <question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR24P01.xml" skills="7">
        <question-text>It can be inferred from the information in paragraph 1 that the theoretical decision-making process</question-text>
        <answer-list>
            <answer-text>involves only the decision maker</answer-text>
            <answer-text>requires the contemplation of numerous options</answer-text>
            <answer-text>is made without the decision unit</answer-text>
            <answer-text>does not work in real situations</answer-text>
        </answer-list>
        <key>2</key>
    </question>
 
    <question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR24P02.xml" skills="1">
        <question-text>The phrase <bg>in conjunction with</bg> in paragraph 1 could best be replaced by</question-text>
        <answer-list>
            <answer-text>along with</answer-text>
            <answer-text>tied to</answer-text>
            <answer-text>apart from</answer-text>
            <answer-text>connected to</answer-text>
        </answer-list>
        <key>1</key>
    </question>
 
    <question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR24P03.xml" skills="6">
        <question-text>All of the following are listed in paragraph 1 as having an effect on decisions EXCEPT</question-text>
        <answer-list>
            <answer-text>evaluation of the problem</answer-text>
            <answer-text>focus on objectives</answer-text>
            <answer-text>generation of options</answer-text>
            <answer-text>open-ended discussions</answer-text>
        </answer-list>
        <key>4</key>
    </question>
   
    <question type='insert' passage-file='ASR24P04.xml' skills='4'>
        <insert-text>
            <b>Additionally, when a decision must be made in a crisis situation, both stress and the speed at which events are progressing can have an effect, often a negative one, on the decision process.</b>
        </insert-text>
        <key>4</key>
    </question>  

    <question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR24P05.xml" skills="1">
        <question-text>The word <bg>ecelectlc</bg> in paragraph 2 is closest in meaning to</question-text>
        <answer-list>
            <answer-text>bizarre</answer-text>
            <answer-text>personal</answer-text>
            <answer-text>mixed</answer-text>
            <answer-text>organized</answer-text>
        </answer-list>
        <key>3</key>
    </question>    
   
    <question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR24P06.xml" skills="7">
        <question-text>It can be inferred from paragraph 3 that a rational actor would be least likely to</question-text>
        <answer-list>
            <answer-text>deal with a specific threat</answer-text>
            <answer-text>work in a random fashion</answer-text>
            <answer-text>ponder various options</answer-text>
            <answer-text>consider disadvantages of options</answer-text>
        </answer-list>
        <key>2</key>
    </question>   
   
    <question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR24P07.xml" skills="2">
        <question-text>The word <bg>it</bg> in paragraph 3 refers to</question-text>
        <answer-list>
            <answer-text>each option</answer-text>
            <answer-text>the best option</answer-text>
            <answer-text>careful analysis</answer-text>
            <answer-text>variation</answer-text>
        </answer-list>
        <key>2</key>
    </question>   
 
    <question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR24P08.xml" skills="8">
        <question-text>Why does the author mention <bg>a satisfier, one who selects the first satisfactory option rather than continuing the decisionmaking process until the optimal decision has been reached</bg> in paragraph 3?</question-text>
        <answer-list>
            <answer-text>A satisfier shows contrasting behavior to a rational actor.</answer-text>
            <answer-text>A satisfier exhibits more common behavior than a rational actor.</answer-text>
            <answer-text>A satisfier is the predecessor of a rational actor.</answer-text>
            <answer-text>A satisfier shares some characteristics with a rational actor.</answer-text>
        </answer-list>
        <key>1</key>
    </question> 
 
    <question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR24P09.xml" skills="1">
        <question-text>The word<bg>placese</bg> in paragraph 4 could best be replaced by</question-text>
        <answer-list>
            <answer-text>locates</answer-text>
            <answer-text>puts</answer-text>
            <answer-text>finds</answer-text>
            <answer-text>sets</answer-text>
        </answer-list>
        <key>2</key>
    </question>

    <question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR24P10.xml" skills="3">
        <question-text>Which of the sentences below expresses the essential information in the highlighted sentence in paragraph 4? <i>Incorrect</i> choices change the meaning in important ways or leave out essential information.</question-text>
        <answer-list>
            <answer-text>Set routines within organizations tend to constrain decisions.</answer-text>
            <answer-text>The restriction of information limits the number of options in a decision.</answer-text>
            <answer-text>Organizations need to set up strict procedures to maximize the effectiveness of decisions.</answer-text>
            <answer-text>Procedures are needed to ensure that decisions are implemented quickly and effectively.</answer-text>
        </answer-list>
        <key>1</key>
    </question>   
 
    <question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR24P11.xml" skills="1">
        <question-text>The word <bg>dynamics</bg> in paragraph 5 is closest in meaning to</question-text>
        <answer-list>
            <answer-text>explosions</answer-text>
            <answer-text>emotions</answer-text>
            <answer-text>philosophies</answer-text>
            <answer-text>interactions</answer-text>
        </answer-list>
        <key>4</key>
    </question>

    <question type="multichoice" passage-file="ASR24P12.xml" skills="5">
        <question-text>According to paragraph 5, what is the end result of political bargaining within an organization?</question-text>
        <answer-list>
            <answer-text>No decision is ever reached.</answer-text>
            <answer-text>Differing interests and motives are changed.</answer-text>
            <answer-text>No one is completely satisfied with the final outcome.</answer-text>
            <answer-text>The members of the decision unit leave the unit.</answer-text>
        </answer-list>
        <key>3</key>
    </question>
           
    <question type='select.1' passage-file='ASR24P13.xml' skills='9'>
        <direction-text>An introductory sentence or a brief summary of the passage is provided below. Complete the summary by selecting the THREE answer choices that express the most important ideas in the passage. Some sentences do not belong in the summary because they express ideas that are not presented in the passage or are minor ideas in the passage.  <i><b>This question is worth 2 points.</b></i>
        </direction-text>
        
        <intro-text>
            <b>This passage presents different models for analyzing the process of decision making.</b>
        </intro-text>
        
        <answer-list>
            <answer>
                <answer-text>One model looks at how satisfied all participants are after a given decision has been made.</answer-text>
            </answer>
            <answer>
                <answer-text>One model looks at how organizational structure and procedures influence a decision and how much a decision has been limited by these procedures.</answer-text>
            </answer>
            <answer>
                <answer-text>One model looks at how much a decision-making process has been manipulated and limited by factions within the organization.</answer-text>
            </answer>
            <answer>
                <answer-text>One model looks at how rational actors are able to work within organizational structures and routines to achieve optimal solutions.</answer-text>
            </answer>
            <answer>
                <answer-text>One model looks at how the decision-making process differs in diverse areas such as psychology, sociology, business, government, history, mathematics, and statistics.</answer-text>
            </answer>
            <answer>
                <answer-text>One model looks at how well a decision maker has analyzed a problem and possible solutions to achieve the optimal solution.</answer-text>
            </answer>
        </answer-list>
        
        <key>0.1..2</key>
    
    </question>  
                                                                                          
</question-list>   


