<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage>
    <passage-text>
        <div align="center">
            <b>Species</b>
        </div>
        <br/>
            Millions of different species exist on the earth. These millions of species, which have
        evolved over billions of years, are the result of two distinct but simultaneously occurring
        processes: the processes of <b>speciation</b> and <b>extinction</b>.
        <br/>
            One of the processes that affects the number of species on earth is <b>speciation</b>,
        which results when one species diverges into two distinct species as a result of disparate
        natural selection in separate environments. Geographic isolation is one common
        mechanism that fosters speciation; speciation as a result of geographic isolation occurs
        when two populations of a species become separated for long periods of time into areas
        with different environmental conditions. After the two populations are separated, they
        evolve independently; if this divergence continues long enough, members of the two
        distinct populations eventually become so different genetically that they are two distinct
        species rather than one. The process of speciation may occur within hundreds of years for
        organisms that reproduce rapidly, but for most species the process of speciation can take
        thousands to millions of years. One example of speciation is the early fox, which over time
        evolved into two distinct species, the gray fox and the arctic fox. The early fox separated
        into populations which evolved differently in response to very different environments as the
        populations moved in different directions, one to colder northern climates and the other to
        warmer southern climates. The northern population adapted to cold weather by developing
        heavier fur, shorter ears, noses, and legs, and white fur to camouflage itself in the snow. The
        southern population adapted to warmer weather by developing lighter fur and longer ears,
        noses, and legs and keeping its darker fur for better camouflage protection.
        <br/>
            Another of the processes that affects the number of species on earth is <b>extinction</b>,
        which refers to the situation in which a species ceases to exist. When environmental
        conditions change, a species needs to adapt to the new environmental conditions, or
        it may become extinct. Extinction of a species is not a rare occurrence but is instead a
        rather commonplace one: it has, in fact, been estimated that more than 99 percent of the.species
        that have ever existed have become extinct. Extinction may occur when a species
        fails to adapt to evolving environmental conditions in a limited area, a process known as
        background extinction. In contrast, a broader and more abrupt extinction, known as mass
        extinction, may come about as a result of a catastrophic event or global climatic change.
        When such a catastrophic event or global climatic change occurs, some species are able to
        adapt to the new environment, while those that are unable to adapt become extinct. From
        geological and fossil evidence, it appears that at least five great mass extinctions have
        occurred; the last mass extinction occurred approximately 65 million years ago, when the
        dinosaurs became extinct after 140 million years of existence on earth, marking the end of
        the Mesozoic Era and the beginning of the Cenozoic Era.
        <br/>
            The fact that millions of species are in existence today is evidence that speciation has
        clearly kept well ahead of extinction. In spite of the fact that there have been numerous
        periods of mass extinction, there is clear evidence that periods of mass extinction have
        been followed by periods of dramatic increases in new species to fill the void created by the
        mass extinctions, though it may take 10 million years or more following a mass extinction
        for biological diversity to be rebuilt through speciation. When the dinosaurs disappeared
        65 million years ago, for example, the evolution and speciation of mammals increased
        spectacularly over the millions of years that ensued.
    </passage-text>
</passage>