<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage scroll0='20' scroll='20'>
    <passage-text>
        <div align="center">
            <b>Ella Deloria</b>
        </div>
        <br/>
            In was not until her posthumous novel <i>Waterlily</i> was published in 1988 that Ella C.
        Deloria became known for her literary ability in addition to her already-established reputation
        in the academic arena of linguistics and ethnology. During her lifetime, she was recognized
        for the linguistic ability and cultural sensitivity that went into the production of a collection
        of traditional short stories entitled <i>Dakota Texts</i> (1932). After her death, her versions of
        a number of longer traditional stories and the novel <i>Waterlily</i> were published; with the
        publication of <i>Waterlily</i> came the recognition of her true literary ability and the awareness
        that it was the strength of her literary ability, in addition to her linguistic expertise and her
        deep cultural understanding, that had made her versions of traditional stories so compelling.
        <br/>
            Ella Cara Deloria was born into a Nakata-speaking family in 1889; however, she
        grew up among the Lakota people in North Dakota, where her father was a leader in the
        Episcopal Church. Her father, the son of a traditional Nakata medicine man, valued both the
        cultural traditions of his family and those of the country of his citizenship. As a result, Deloria
        primarily spoke Nakata at home and Lakota when she was out in the community, and
        she was well versed there in the cultural traditions of her Sioux ancestors (with a complex
        kinship structure in which all of a child's father's brothers are also considered fathers, all of
        a child's mother's sisters are also considered mothers, and all of the children of all these
        mothers and fathers are considered siblings). Her education, however, was in English, at the
        Episcopalian Saint Elizabeth Mission School and the All Saints School. After high school,
        she attended Oberlin College in Ohio for one year, and then she transferred to Columbia
        University to study linguistics under Franz Boas, the founder of American Indian linguistics.
        <br/>
            After graduating from Columbia, she was encouraged by Boas to collect and record
        traditional Lakota stories. She was in a unique position to take on this task because of her
        fluency in the Lakota language as well as in English, her understanding from childhood of
        the complexities and subtleties of Lakota culture, and her linguistic training from Columbia.
        The result of her research was the <i>Dakota Texts</i>, a bilingual collection of 64 short stories.
        To create this remarkable work, Deloria was able to elicit stories from venerable Sioux
        elders, without need for translators and with <bg>an awareness of appropriately respectful
        behavior</bg>. She listened to the stories as numerous generations had before her, and then,
        unlike previous generations, recorded them in writing-initially in Lakota and later in English.
        She transcribed them essentially as they were told but with her own understanding of the
        nuances of what was being told.
        <br/>
            In addition to the shorter stories that were published in <i>Dakota Texts</i>, Deloria spent
        1937 working on transcribing a number of longer and more complicated texts, which were
        not published until after her death. "Iron Hawk: Oglala Culture Hero" (1993) presents the
        diverse elements of the culture-hero genre; "The Buffalo People" (1994) focuses on the
        importance of tribal education in building character; "A Sioux Captive" (1994) tells the story
        of a Lakota woman who rescued her husband from the Crow; "The Prairie Dogs" (1994)
        describes the sense of hope offered by the Sioux warrior-society ceremonies and dances.
        <br/> 
            Her novel <i>Waterlily</i>, which was first published 40 years after it was completed
        and 17 years after her death, reflects her true literary talent as well as her accumulated
        understanding of traditional culture and customs. The novel recounts the fictional story of
        the difficult life of the title character, with a horrendous childhood experience as witness to
        a deadly enemy raid and a first marriage terminated by the untimely death of her husband in
        a smallpox epidemic, and comes to a close with the hopeful expectations of an impending
        second marriage. At the same time, it presents a masterful account of life in a nineteenthcentury
        Sioux community with its detailed descriptions of interpersonal relationships and
        attitudes, everyday tasks and routines, and special ceremonies and celebrations.
    </passage-text>
</passage>