<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage>
    <passage-text>
        <div align="center">
            <b>Decisions</b>
        </div>
        <br/>
            In a theoretical model of decision making, a decision is defined as the process of
        selecting one option from among a group of options for implementation. Decisions are
        formed by a <b>decision maker</b>, the one who actually chooses the final option, in conjunction
        with a <b>decision unit</b>, all of those in the organization around the decision maker who take
        part in the process. In this theoretical model, the members of the decision unit react
        to an unidentified problem by studying the problem, determining the objectives of the
        organization, formulating options, evaluating the strengths and weaknesses of each of
        the options, and reaching a conclusion. Many different factors can have an effect on the
        decision, including the nature of the problem itself, external forces exerting an influence
        on the organization, the internal dynamics of the decision unit, and the personality of the
        decision maker.
        <br/>
            During recent years, decision making has been studied systematically by drawing
        from such diverse areas of study as psychology, sociology, business, government, history,
        mathematics, and statistics. Analyses of decisions often emphasize one of three principal
        conceptual perspectives (though often the approach that is actually employed is somewhat
        eclectic).
        <br/>
            In the oldest of the three approaches, decisions are made by a <b>rational actor</b>, who
        makes a particular decision directly and purposefully in response to a specific threat from
        the external environment. It is assumed that this rational actor has clear objectives in mind,
        develops numerous reasonable options, considers the advantages and disadvantages of
        each option carefully, chooses the best option after careful analysis, and then proceeds
        to implement it fully. A variation of the rational actor model is a decision maker who is a
        <b>satisfier</b>, one who selects the first satisfactory option rather than continuing the decisionmaking
        process until the optimal decision has been reached.
        <br/>
            A second perspective places an emphasis on the impact of routines on decisions
        within organizations. It demonstrates how organizational structures and routines such as
        standard operating procedures tend to limit the decision-making process in a variety of
        ways, perhaps by restricting the information.available to the decision unit, by restricting the
        breadth of options among which the decision unit may choose, or by inhibiting the ability of
        the organization to implement the decision quickly and effectively once it has been taken.
        Pre-planned routines and standard operating procedures are essential to coordinate the
        efforts of large numbers of people in massive organizations. However, these same routines
        and procedures can also have an inhibiting effect on the ability of the organization to arrive
        at optimal decisions and implement them efficiently. In this sort of decision-making process,
        organizations tend to take not the optimal decision but the decision that best fits within the
        permitted operating parameters outlined by the organization.
        <br/>
            A third conceptual perspective emphasizes the internal dynamics of the decision unit
        and the extent to which decisions are based on political forces within the organization. This
        perspective demonstrates how bargaining among individuals who have different interests
        and motives and varying levels of power in the decision unit leads to eventual compromise
        that is not the preferred choice of any of the members of the decision unit.
        6 Each of these three perspectives on the decision-making process demonstrates a
        different point of view on decision making, a different lens through which the decisionmaking
        process can be observed. It is safe to say that decision making in most
        organizations shows marked influences from each perspective; i.e., an organization strives
        to get as close as possible to the rational model in its decisions, yet the internal routines
        and dynamics of the organization come into play in the decision.
    </passage-text>
</passage>