<?xml version="1.0"?>
<passage>
    <passage-text>
        <div align="center">
            <b>Early Autos</b>
        </div>
        <br/>
            America's passion for the automobile developed rather quickly in the beginning of
        the twentieth century. At the turn of that century, there were few automobiles, or horseless
        carriages, as they were called at the time, and those that existed were considered frivolous
        playthings of the rich. They were rather fragile machines that sputtered and smoked and
        broke down often; they were expensive toys that could not be counted on to get one where
        one needed to go; they could only be afforded by the wealthy class, who could afford both
        the expensive upkeep and the inherent delays that resulted from the use of a machine
        that tended to break down time and again. These early automobiles required repairs so
        frequently both because their engineering was at an immature stage and because roads
        were unpaved and often in poor condition. Then, when breakdowns occurred, there were
        no services such as roadside gas stations or tow trucks to assist drivers needing help in
        their predicament. Drivers of horse-drawn carriages considered the horseless mode of
        transportation foolhardy, preferring instead to rely on their four-legged "engines," which they
        considered a tremendously more dependable and cost-effective means of getting around.
        <br/> 
            Automobiles in the beginning of the twentieth century were quite unlike today's
        models. Many of them were electric cars, even though the electric models had quite a
        limited range and needed to be recharged frequently at electric charging stations; many
        others were powered by steam, though it was often required that drivers of steam cars
        be certified steam engineers due to the dangers inherent in operating a steam-powered
        machine. The early automobiles also lacked much emphasis on body design; in fact, they
        were often little more than benches on wheels, though by the end of the first decade of
        the century they had progressed to leather-upholstered chairs or sofas on thin wheels that
        absorbed little of the incessant pounding associated with the movement of these machines.
        <br/> 
            In spite of the rather rough and undeveloped nature of these early horseless carriages,
        something about them grabbed people's imagination, and their use increased rapidly,
        though not always smoothly. In the first decade of the last century, roads were shared by the
        horse-drawn and horseless variety of carriages, a situation that was rife with problems and
        required strict measures to control the incidents and accidents that resulted when two such
        different modes of transportation were used in close proximity. New York City, for example,
        banned horseless vehicles from Central Park early in the century because they had been
        involved in so many accidents, often causing injury or death; then, in 1904, New York state
        felt that it was necessary to control automobile traffic by placing speed limits of 20 miles
        per hour in open areas, 15 miles per hour in villages, and 10 miles per hour in cities or
        areas of congestion. However, the measures taken were less a means of limiting use of the
        automobile and more a way of controlling the effects of an invention whose use increased
        dramatically in a relatively short period of time. Under 5,000 automobiles were sold in
        the United States for a total cost of approximately $5 million in 1900, while considerably
        more cars, 181,000, were sold for $215 million in 1910, and by the middle of the 1920s,
        automobile manufacturing had become the top industry in the United States and accounted
        for 6 percent of the manufacturing in the country.
    </passage-text>
</passage>